♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
Is Uno there?
[Cita] He is inside. Why?
[Karla] I think he's a spy.
Maybe he works for Red Regalia.
[Cita] What?!
[Uno] The truth is,
I actually work for Colonel Mercado.
Why are you here?
I need to secure the laptop
that was turned over to Sir Padua.
Where is he?
[Uno] But he's missing in action.
[Cita] Is Atoy still alive?!
- Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom.
- Miss… Miss.
Don't say that.
I really admire Brother Atoy.
Do you admire me too?
Ouch. Ouch!
What's wrong? [chuckles]
Is Atoy here?
We're looking for him. We need his help.
[in English] I don't want to be a Regalia.
And I'm ashamed to be
the child of your husband!
[Gavin on phone] Mom, I love you.
But you're also an enabler
of Dad's evil behavior.
[Karla] He's Brother Atoy's colleague.
This is Gavin, my friend.
- Future boyfriend of Karla.
- What?
[in English] Manifesting.
We're safe here.
How can we be safe if Daddy isn't here?
Where are you, Atoy?
[mysterious voice] Psst.
[gasps]
- [mysterious voice] Psst.
- [gasps]
Son of a thread.
[music swells]
PREVIOUSLY
[music fades]
You are the son of the thread.
Emerson, listen.
I need your help
and the help of your fellow
children of the thread.
[pensive music playing]
[Emerson] What is this?
Why--
Are you haunting me?
Why is your mouth moving in the picture?
You're speaking,
but only your mouth is moving?
[quirky music playing]
What is this? Are you haunting me?
Like Tonet?
[Atoy] No, no!
Emerson, I'm not a ghost yet. Be serious!
Act. Prove yourself.
I need the help
of the children of the thread.
[whimsical music playing]
- [mouthing] Emerson!
- [Cita] Emerson!
[babbling]
[Cita] Emerson!
Emerson!
Emerson, wake up! Wake up…
Ame!
Emerson, wake up.
- [Ame] I'm here, Miss Cita!
- Wake up!
Hurry! Emerson!
Emerson!
- [babbling]
- [mouthing] I'll handle it, miss.
[Cita] Quick, quick.
- [babbling]
- This will wake up Emerson.
[babbling]
- [metals clanging]
- [gasping]
What was that?
What was that?!
[sneaky music playing]
What was that, Ame?
That was so loud,
my eardrums almost broke.
[Ame] Sorry.
We didn't know how to wake you up.
We found you having a nightmare!
[Ame] My gosh!
[melancholi music playing]
[puffed exhale]
I dreamt of Atoy.
He said he needs our help…
The children of the thread.
[both] Help?!
[pensive music playing]
Let's save him.
[Emerson] Where's Uno?
He said he was coming here today.
[Gavin, in English] Hello. Good morning!
[Emerson] Ame.
Maybe you need to call Karla
and Brother Kurt.
Tell them we need an emergency meeting.
Right now.
Wait. Isn't that too much?
Because it was just a dream.
My gut feeling is different.
[Ame] Oh. Oh, okay.
I'll fetch Karla.
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
- [scratches]
- [snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
- [gun cocks]
- [gunshots]
[gunshots]
[clicking]
[snipping]
[music swells]
[electronic blipping]
I'd like to buy the pink shampoo, please.
Oh. Wait, pretty girl.
There's only one left.
Good thing you bought it
before we ran out.
- Shampoo, please! Hey!
- Hey, Janice.
Pay, pay.
Uh--
- This woman.
- Sis, sis, I bought that first.
What did you say?
I bought it first!
[vendor] Hey, Janice!
What's wrong with you?
That's for the child! She bought it first!
- Whatever!
- [vendor] Give it here!
I have somewhere to go.
I need to take a bath.
You're terrible! She's Olga's daughter!
You'll be in trouble.
Give her the shampoo, quick!
Give it.
[Janice] Really?
Olga's child is dead.
- [smirks]
- [vendor] You're annoying.
What are you? A ghost?
You're a fake daughter!
[heavy music playing]
[smirks]
I'm not fake.
Why are you saying I'm fake?
- Olga is a scammer.
- [vendor] Janice!
So, for sure, you're her fake daughter!
[music swells]
Don't insult my mom.
And my sister died.
And I'm definitely not fake.
Not like your lips.
- [gasps] Hey!
- [vendor chuckles]
My lips aren't fake, okay.
I took after Angelina Jolie.
[chuckles]
And what you're saying is impossible.
Don't mess with me!
[suspicious music playing]
Olga only has one child!
So, I'm sure that scammer Olga
is just using you to get back
into the barangay, to get aid again!
Olga is a scammer!
I know her modus.
[smirks] Don't mess with me.
You know, you're the one who needs aid.
Aid of goodness!
Because you lack that.
[music fades]
- Hey! Oh!
- [laughing]
Janice, what are you doing?!
You're fighting with a child!
- [cackles]
- Are you okay, pretty girl?
Oh, you got dirty.
It's okay if I fall and get dirty.
But my mom will still be beautiful,
- even without bee stings on her lips,
- [chuckles]
unlike you.
[pensive music playing]
- You're really getting…
- [vendor] Hey. Hey, hey, Janice!
- Huh?
- You're getting on my nerves!
- [Charmi] Hey!
- [squeals]
- Come here.
- Ouch, you're hurting me!
- [shrieking]
- Pull my hair instead.
Let's see if you won't swap faces!
- [clamoring]
- [screaming]
[music fades]
I called you all
because Atoy sent me an SOS.
He called you?
No. I dreamt of him.
He said he needs the help
of the children of the thread.
[sneaky music playing]
Children of what?
What? Children of what?
Children of the thread.
Our group, inspired by Brother Atoy.
Of course, Thread 1,
our boss, Boss Emerson.
Thread 2, me.
Thread 3, MIA, Brother Kurt.
[Karla] He'll come here later.
Our mini thread, our muse.
[Audrey] Oh!
I'm part of that too, right?
Yes.
You're the…
adopted thread.
- [Karla, in Engilsh] Legit.
- [Uno] Ah!
So, does that mean
I'm included, because you called me?
Right?
Hmm. Maybe.
[music fades]
You can be…
Tape Measure, Pin Tape Measure.
[sneaky music playing]
Who-- Who…
What's that?
I don't understand. What?
Tape measure. Tape measure.
For measurement. [in English] Measurement.
Because we still need to measure you.
You're not really part
of the children of the thread yet.
We don't know your skill set,
your capacities, your capabilities.
Honestly, you haven't contributed yet,
compared to all of us.
[music swells]
[in English] Going back to the discussion.
[music fades]
A special personal mission must be done
by the children of the thread.
We'll call this
[in English] "Operation Atoy…
[suspicious music playing]
…Where are you?"
Do you have intel
on Agent Padua's location?
Because, honestly, we don't
have any information about him.
What about you?
Do you have any info
on Brother Atoy's last mission?
[in English] Yes.
[in English] To retrieve
the high-state decoder.
But he was attacked
by an unidentified syndicate group
possibly connected to the Zahran Embassy.
Wait. Was this the mission where they
pretended to be the Sokolov brothers?
The question is…
Who among them
is holding Agent Padua?
That's what we're trying to find out.
Could it be the ambassador?
[music fades]
It's possible, but…
Maybe not.
Because as far as I know,
our current intel says
he's not in the country.
[suspicious music playing]
[Samir, in English]
Nice to meet you, Sir Dmitri.
[in English] This is Samir.
[in English] He is the one
I've been telling you about.
[Audrey, in English] Help! Help!
- [in English] Ambassador! Ambassador!
- [Audrey, in English] Help!
[in English] Some guy in a mask
jumped over the kitchen counter.
[in English] He ran and hit my dad
and the ambassador over the head and…
he climbed out the hole in the window.
[in English] But you're okay, Ms. Audrey.
[in English] He is a master of disguise.
[Samir, in English] He pretends
to be a window cleaner
to sneak into the embassy.
[in English] Do you know this man?
The ambassador's bodyguard.
His name is Samir.
S… Samir?
I have a strong feeling
he's the reason Atoy is missing.
[tense music playing]
[in English] Can you please
give him some food? He--
[in English] He hasn't eaten
for days. If--
[in English] If he-- If he dies,
you will never know where the laptop is.
- [in English] No.
- [in English] You don't understand.
[in English] If he dies, you will not know
where the laptop is.
[in English] I said, no!
[ominous music playing]
[speaks in Russian] Delicious!
[in English] That means "delicious".
[in English] You see, I learned
your language, Tagalog.
[in English] Good, right?
[inhales]
Hmm? Smell.
[in English] Oh, look.
[in English] Wow, wow.
[in English] Sir. I am--
[in English] I am very, very hungry.
[in English] Can you… Can you give me
some of that, please, sir?
- [in English] Please. Sir. Sir, please.
- [in English] What did you say?
- [in English] Give me some, please.
- [Samir, in English] Sir. I like it
- when you call me "Sir".
- [in English] Please.
- [in English] Yes, please, sir.
- Oh.
[in English] Please. Give me.
[Samir, in English] You want some?
[speaks in Russian] Do you want it?
[coughs]
[in English] I'm very, very hungry, sir.
- [in English] Please, please. Please, sir.
- [speaks in Russian] Take it.
- [in Russian] Take it.
- [in English] Please. Ah! Ah… Please, sir.
- [in Russian] Take it. Take it!
- [in English] Ah! Very, very hungry, sir.
[Samir shouts]
- [groans]
- [tense music playing]
[speaks in Russian] Filthy dog!
[grunts and groans]
[tense music playing]
[speaks in Russian] Punch him!
[Atoy, in English] No.
[grunting and groaning]
- [groaning]
- [music swells]
[grunting and groaning]
[music fades]
So, what are we waiting for?
Let's go to the embassy
to spy on Samir.
We can't.
The embassy is closed now.
It's the weekend.
Closed?
If Samir is in the Philippines,
then where could he be now?
[in English] Maybe we can go,
um, exercise, running?
[in English] Sometimes I go running
in the Acacia Grove on Saturday.
[in English] You've been there?
He invited me to jog in a park, um…
[in English] Acacia Grove.
He wanted to date me, get to know me.
[Audrey sighs]
[Gavin, in English]
What are you saying, Auntie?
[in English] So, what I'm saying is,
I can try to bump into him…
To get information from him.
[Gavin, in English] That's too risky.
[in English] And besides,
we're hiding from Dad. Especially you.
Gavin, I don't care.
I just want to help.
[in English] I want to find Atoy
just as much as you guys.
Didn't Emerson say we need to act now?
Okay.
So where is this jogging park
you're talking about, Mama Mary?
Oh, no! Um…
Mrs. Cutter. No! I mean, Ms. Audrey.
Because that's where it will happen.
The mission of the children of the thread.
[in English] Special personal mission.
[in English] "Operation Atoy,
Where are you?"
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[in English] Lester, TJ, keep
a closer watch on this dog.
[in English] It's just the two of you.
[in English] Don't let him escape.
[in English] Let's go.
[suspicious music playing]
[Lily] Atoy. Atoy, can you hear me?
Atoy, here. Eat this, quickly. [grunts]
[sighs, panting]
[panting] Eat, here.
[music fades]
‪[sighs]
[Lily] Atoy.
- [sighs]
- [tense music playing]
Where…
- [in English] Please, Sir. Ah!
- [speaks in Russian] Take it! Take it!
[in English] Ah! Very, very hungry, sir.
[Samir shouts]
[groans]
[in English] The cufflinks.
We'll use this in the first stage
of our escape.
We'll escape.
[sighs]
[Atoy] Let's go. [inhales]
‪[gasps]
- [clatters]
- [sighs]
[sighs]
[grunts]
- [groaning, heavy breathing]
- [gate lock rattling]
Atoy, Atoy.
Here, here.
Hold this, hold this, hold this.
[gasps, winces]
[groaning, heavy breathing]
- [squealing]
- [clamoring]
How is this going to--
- [mocking chuckle]
- [sneaky music playing]
- What?!
- Damn!
Huh?! Get out of here!
It's raining. You'll multiply!
You think just because she's a child,
you'll fight with her?! I'll fight you!
The nerve of this woman!
Oh, let's see now if you don't go
back to your doctor,
so you can get your lips vulcanized!
- [scoffs]
- [music fades]
Are you okay, child?
That woman.
That Janice!
Are you okay?
Oh, child?
Don't be sad.
Forget what that frog Janice said.
You're not a fake child.
Mama Olga loves you very much.
- You know?
- Mmm?
I felt
she loves me, because she told me.
- Uh-huh.
- And then she hugged me!
See? I told you,
your Mama Olga really loves you.
- I feel sad.
- Oh?
Because they called her a scammer.
But Mama is really kind.
Hmm. Mm-hmm.
I hope
I won't be separated from Mama.
[Charmi] Do you know Ibyang's real parent?
- It's Atoy.
- [in English] For real?!
That's why even if I want
to take care of Ibyang
and assume the role of her real mother,
of course, that wouldn't be right.
I still need
to give her back to her true parent.
To Atoy.
[gentle music playing]
Just be happy.
Okay? Smile now.
Smile now.
See? You're so beautiful when you smile.
And child, don't mention this
to your Mama Olga, okay?
Because you know,
she'll pull out all the teeth
of that bully Janice.
That bully will get uglier.
Just ignore her.
[pleasant music playing]
I thought
only kids like me bully others.
But there are adults who do it too.
And her name even sounds like…
Janine!
[tense music playing]
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Tape Measure, this is Thread 1.
I still don't have a sighting
of Tailor AFAM.
How are your sightings over there?
[in English] Over.
Thread 1,
I just want to tell you
that the code name you gave me,
I really don't like it.
Tape Measure?
It's old. Don't you have another?
Well, what else?
There aren't many other options.
What do you want? Safety pin? Or…
What else is possible?
Safety pin or button. Choose one.
What's your status there?
Nothing.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Samir isn't here.
I mean, no visuals of Tailor AFAM.
I'm thinking, if he doesn't show up here,
we're just wasting time.
Mama Mary, Adopted Thread.
[in English] Are you guys ready?
Reminder, Thread 1.
Mama Mary and Adopted Thread
don't have earpieces. Over.
Oh, right. Right.
[in English] Sorry.
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
Where could Olga be?
We're dead if Boss Red finds out--
Psst!
Hide that!
- [thug] Sorry, boss.
- Someone might see that here!
Hide it! Hide it!
- [in English] Sorry, boss. Sorry, boss.
- Hide it!
[mysterious music playing]
[sharp inhale]
[line ringing]
Boss, we can't spot Olga.
Some people say she jogs here often, but…
Not even a shadow.
We also went to her house.
They said she already moved.
She's been gone a while.
Keeps moving around.
[in English] Yes, boss.
[in English] Yes, boss. Yes.
We'll keep searching, boss.
[in English] Yes, boss.
- [phone blips]
- [in English] Boss.
What do we do now?
Where do we find Olga?
I don't know!
That woman and that mouse Ibyang
are harder to find.
I'm sure they're hiding in Tabang Lupa.
They will be easier to catch there.
Boss, let's eat first. I'm hungry.
There!
That's what you're good at!
Feeding that snake in your stomach!
Let's go, let's go.
[rousing music playing]
[in English] Mama Mary is locked on.
[in English] Yes.
[Uno] Hmm.
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Yes.
[Gavin] Hey, Tape Measure, behave.
She's Master Cutter's ex,
so you can't flirt with her.
Unless you want trouble.
Relax, Adopted Thread.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[sharp exhale]
She's not my type.
You might be forgetting.
[music fades]
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Tape Measure, Tape Measure.
I have a sighting of Tailor AFAM.
[in English] I already have visuals.
[in English] Be alert.
- [huffs]
- [music swells]
- [electronic blipping]
- [tense music playing]
Let me just remind me of your mission.
[in English] Bump into Samir,
flirt, lure him into a date,
and find out where the Master Cutter is.
[Gavin, in English] Good luck, Auntie.
Wait, wait, Gavin.
[Audrey] Do you see Emerson?
What's he doing?
- [Emerson, in English] Here, over there.
- [in English] Sir, that's Audrey, right?
- Auntie, let's go. Let's go, Auntie!
- Is that him? Huh? Ah?
- [in English] Okay. What! No, no!
- [Kurt] That's him!
The… The ambassador's bodyguard. That's…
Samir! That's Samir!
[Samir, in English] Where do you think
you are going?
Go to hell!
[grunting and groaning]
‪UP NEXT
There, I… [gasps]
I removed it.
[speaks softly] I removed it.
[in English] What are you talking about?
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by:
Geraldine M. Andong